# Alex O'Callaghan

<u>aocallaghan@outlook.com</u> https://alexocallaghan.com | https://github.com/awocallaghan

# **Summary**

A highly motivated and passionate software developer who enjoys solving problems and acquiring new skills. I have recently completed my bachelor's degree in Computer Science at the University of Southampton, and have experience working in a professional software development environment. In addition to my academic and professional experience, I have further developed my skills by completing projects and experimenting with code in my spare time.

My main passion is web development as I love to create things that can be used to help people in their everyday lives and I believe websites and mobile applications are one of the most effective media for achieving this. I have experience with a variety of programming languages, styles, and frameworks, stay up to date with the latest modern technologies, and have experience with popular **JavaScript** framework/libraries such as **Angular**, **React**, and **jQuery**. In addition, I am comfortable with an array of server-side languages such as **PHP**, **C#**, **Java**, and **JavaScript** (**Node.js**).

#### **Education**

# 2014-2017 University of Southampton: BSc Computer Science (Hons 2:1)

Year one:

Programming 1 & 2

Algorithmics

- Foundations of Computer Science
- Computer Systems

#### Year two:

- Programming 3
- Distributed Systems and Networks
- Life in the Cosmos
- Intelligent Systems

- Data Management
- Professional Development
  - Foundations of Computer Science
- Software Modelling and Design
- Theory of Computing
- Software Engineering Group Project
- Programming Language Concepts
- Interaction Design

#### Year three:

- Part III Individual Project
- Global Challenges
- Social Enterprise

- Cyber Security
- Computational Biology
- · Game Design and Development

#### 2012-2014 Queensmead High School

A Levels: Computing (A), Maths (A), Further Maths (A), EPQ (Computing) (A)

#### 2007-2012 Queensmead High School

GCSEs:

13 GCSEs grade A\*-B, including English B and Maths A\*

#### **Experience**

### October 2017-December 2017 – Full stack web developer

I worked for three months as a remote full stack web developer leading the development of a new job application platform. My responsibilities included defining, prioritising and completing development tasks to ensure the implementation and deployment of an **ASP .NET MVC + Angular** MVP web application on **Azure** meeting the start-up's business and technical objectives.

# 2016-2017 – Final Year Project (BSc Computer Science, University of Southampton)

As part of my BSc Computer Science degree I developed a data visualisation web application to help University lecturers analyse how students are watching their uploaded video lectures shared via the web. The application used **Node.js/Express** for the webserver, NoSQL database **RethinkDB** for data storage, and **D3** (**Data Driven Documents**) and **Vue.js** for the frontend data visualisation graph components.

# Summer 2016 - Web Developer at Ascesis Media

During the summer break of my studies I worked as a web developer for digital media agency Ascesis leading the implementation of a **Wordpress** website with bespoke CRM features. My responsibilities included writing bespoke **Wordpress/PHP** plugins and themes, designing and implementing a normalised **MySQL** database schema with efficient queries, as well as being available to support other developers when needed whilst ensuring the project was completed by the deadline to the clients' high standards.

#### 2012-2016 - FootyFeeds

#### Source code: https://github.com/awocallaghan/footyfeeds-angular

FootyFeeds is a project I first started in 2012 in my spare time using **PHP/MySQL** to display football news articles from **RSS** feeds from around the web. As my knowledge grew I remade the website using **Node.js/Express/PostgreSQL** for the backend and **Angular, HTML, SASS** for the frontend. This project has given me practical experience of using **git** and build tools like **Gulp** in a development workflow and marketing a website using **social media** such as **Twitter** and **Facebook**.

#### 2014 - Map of Crime in London in 2013

See the code: <a href="https://github.com/awocallaghan/awocallaghan.github.io/tree/master/crime">https://github.com/awocallaghan.github.io/tree/master/crime</a>
This project was part of my EPQ (Extended Project Qualification) for which I chose to develop a map of crime in London in 2013 as I was interested in seeing how technology could be used to help tackle crime. I implemented a web-based interactive map of crime using open data from data.gov.uk and Google Maps API.

#### 2014 - Website Design for Audbern Ltd

See it: http://www.audbern.co.uk

I delivered a new website design for Audbern Ltd, a ground rent buying company. My responsibilities included liaising with the client to clarify the requirements for the website. This project required me to design a website using HTML/CSS, upload the webpages using SFTP and set up/install a CMS. This work gave me experience in working to a deadline and enhanced my communication skills.

More: http://alexocallaghan.com/projects/